[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：HTML在20世纪末推出时还不是最先进的
&gt;&gt; Douglas: HTML was not state of the art when it was introduced in the late 20th
世纪。
century.
它的目的是为简单的文档查看器，而不是打算
It was intended for simple document viewers it was not intended to be
应用程序交付平台。
an application delivery platform.
我们坚持使用它作为应用程序交付平台，因为我们需要一个
We insisted on using it as an application delivery platform because we needed one
这是最好的东西，所以我们用了它。
and that was the best thing available, so we used it.
但它并不是很适合我们想要做的事情。
But it was not well suited to what we wanted to do.
一开始很多人看着它
A lot of people looked at it in the beginning and
认为它不具备所需的能力，他们是对的。
thought it didn't have what it takes, and they were right.
但我们还是继续做了。
But we went ahead and did it anyway.
因此，从那时起，Web标准就从一个天真的超文本系统发展而来
So since then, the web standards were grown from a naive hypertext system
在强烈的高度不稳定的竞争压力下。
under intense highly unstable competitive pressure.
当网景和微软试图通过操纵网络来摧毁对方时
As Netscape and Microsoft attempted to destroy each other by manipulating web
标准，它并不是为做所有这些Ajax东西而设计的。
standards and it wasn't designed to do all of this Ajax stuff.
它的成功归功于许多非常聪明的人，他们找到了制造它的方法
Its success is due to a lot of very clever people who found ways to make it
尽管其设计限制，但仍能工作。
work despite its design limitations.
HTML是对SGML的巨大改进。
HTML was a huge improvement over SGML.
主要是因为它在任何时候都会简单得多
Primarily in that it was much a simpler anytime you take something that's
太复杂和
too complex and
把它变成简单的东西，得到一般都在使它变得更好。
turn into something it's simple, get generally are making it better.
不幸的是，它们也使其更具弹性。
Unfortunately, they also made it more resilient.
SGML中的规则之一是如果您当时不认识标签
One of the rules in SGML was if you don't recognize the tag then
彻底失败，什么都没发生，他们认为这对网络来说太多了。
total failure, nothing happens and they thought that was too much for the web.
所以在网络上，规则是如果你看到一个标签
So instead on the web, the rule is if you see a tag and
您不认识它，忽略它并继续解析它，它就会工作。
you don't recognize it, ignore it and keep parsing and it works.
这实际上对网络有好处，因为这意味着我们可以升级。
And that's actually been good for the web because it meant that we could upgrade.
我们可以具有向前和向后兼容性，因为浏览器将
We could have forward and backward compatibility because the browsers would
当他们进入和离开标准时忽略差异。
be ignoring the differences as they enter and leave the standards.
不幸的是，黑暗的一面是曾经，也许现在仍然存在，
Unfortunately the dark side of that is that there were, maybe still are,
不能正确编写HTML的不称职的Web管理员。
incompetent web masters who could not correctly write HTML.
而且浏览器会做一些英雄般的事情来尝试有意义
And the browsers would do heroic stuff to try to make sense
他们正在写的东西。
out of the stuff that they are writing.
这变成了安全漏洞，我们将在第三天讨论。
Which turned into security exploits which we'll talk about on the third day.
所以HTML的原始形式
So the original formation of HTML
作者实际上无法控制演示文稿。
authors had virtually no control over presentation.
而且这件事并没有预料到除了简单的文档之外的应用程序
And the thing didn't anticipate applications beyond simple document
检索，这是我们现在所做的非常小的一部分。
retrieval, which is a very small part of what we're doing now.
它不是内部自洽的。
It's not internally self-consistent.
例如，它提供了两种编写大纲的方法
For example, it provides two ways of writing outlines
一个是嵌套的，一个不是，它是不一致的。
one is nested one is not, it's not consistent.
我们称之为网页的东西不是网页，而是一个卷轴。
And the thing that we call a web page is not a page, it's a scroll.
我希望有一天我们能发明页面，因为页面很棒。
I'm hoping someday we invent pages, cuz pages are great.
页面是文明前进的一大步，
Pages were a big step forward in the march of civilization,
也许有一天网络会赶上这一点。
maybe someday the web will catch up to that.
所以SGML社区讨厌HTML，他们认为它是可憎的。
So the SGML community hated HTML, they thought it was an abomination.
他们不喜欢它被简化的方式
They did not like the way it was simplified and
更重要的是，他们不喜欢它比SGML更受欢迎的方式。
even more than that they did not like the way it was so much more popular than SGML.
所以最终他们接管了W3C
So eventually they took over W3C and
开始改变事物使之更符合他们的喜好。
started changing things to be more to their liking.
例如，他们改变了p的工作方式，p原本是一个分隔符，
For example, they changed the way p worked, p had originally been a separator,
他们把它变成了一个容器。
they turned it into a container.
他们开始了关于语义标记的事情
They started the thing about semantic markup which
结果证明是一种巨大的时间浪费，他们还创建了XML Fiasco。
turned out to be a colossal waste of time and they also created the XML Fiasco.
他们的想法是创建XML，它将是SGML的继承者。
The idea was that they would create XML, which would be the successor of SGML.
它将被用作新的文档格式，以取代HTML和
Which would be used as the new document format replacing HTML and
作为世界上的数据交换格式，它在这两方面都失败了。
be used as the world's data interchange format, it failed at both of those things.
事实证明HTML拒绝死亡
HTML it turned out refused to die and
它仍然是Web的文档格式和
it is still the web's document format and
世界上的数据交换格式是
the world's data interchange format is
杰森。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：但是你说
Jason. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: But you said
你可以谈论神话语义学。道格拉斯：不，我不是
you can talk about mythical semantics. &gt;&gt; Douglas: Not, I am not
来谈论语义标记。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的。
to be talking about semantic markup. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：你得找个人
&gt;&gt; Douglas: You'll have to find someone
否则我就不会告诉你了。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：不，
else to tell about that. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No,
我很好奇为什么你。&GT；&GT；道格拉斯：它没有得到回报，
I'm curious as to why you. &gt;&gt; Douglas: It didn't pay off,
我们花了很多时间在上面
we spent a lot of time on it and
没有得到任何东西。&GT；&GT；扬声器2：你知道，
didn't get anything for it. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: You know,
我们遇到的唯一像这样的人是有残疾的人
the only folks that we run into that like it are people who have disabilities
谁想要语义标记提供一些额外的信息
who want the semantic markup to provide some extra bit of information for
他们。道格拉斯：我非常同情
them. &gt;&gt; Douglas: I have a lot of sympathy for
试图使用网络的残疾人，
people with disabilities who are trying to use the web,
我不认为这是解决办法。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：但是
I don't think that was the solution. &gt;&gt; Douglas: But
我可以理解绝望的程度，与网络提供的东西相比
I can understand being desperate enough that compared to what the web delivers
任何东西看起来都会比你得到的更好。
that anything else might look to be better than what you got.
我可以谈论CSS，但我只是开始咆哮
I could talk about CSS, but I just start ranting and
你不需要听我咆哮，是吗？
you don't need to hear me rant, do you?
不管怎么说，只是，所以
Anyways it's just, so
我的意思是，这是在和一个终于擅长CSS的人交谈
it's talking to someone who's finally gotten good at CSS I mean
很难提高到CSS是真的很难和困难。
it's hard to step up to CSS is really hard and difficult.
最终设计师到达那里
Eventually designers get there and
一旦他们这样做了，斯德哥尔摩的事情似乎就会发生在他们身上。
once they've done it this Stockholm thing seems to happen to them.
这有点像在警察身上看家庭纠纷。
And it's kind of like watching a domestic dispute on cops.
CSS还不错，你只是不像我那样理解它，是的。
CSS isn't bad, you just don't understand it like I do, yeah, yeah, yeah.
无论如何，如果网络上只有HTML和
Anyway if all there was to the web was HTML and
CSS，它现在应该已经被替换了。
CSS, it would have been replaced by now.
网络将不复存在，我们将致力于其他的工作
The web would be gone and we would be working on something else and
这就是证据。
this is the proof of that.
Forrester Research的董事长兼首席执行官乔治·柯罗尼(George Colony)说，
George Colony, the Chairman and CEO of Forrester Research was saying,
另一种软件技术将会出现
Another software technology will come along and
消灭网络，就像它杀死了新闻，Gopher等人一样。
kill off the Web, just as it killed News, Gopher, et al.
在接下来的两三年里，审判日很快就会到来。
And that judgment day will arrive very soon, in the next two to three years.
所以他在2000年预测，到2003年，
So he was predicting in 2000, that by 2003,
网络将会死掉，取而代之的是他所说的X互联网，这
the web would be dead, replaced by what he called the X Internet, which
是一个可执行的互联网应用程序，它是一个应用程序交付系统。
was an app that the executable Internet, it was an application delivery system.
他认为万维网是有缺陷的，因为它所能做的
That he thought that the web was deficient because all it could do
是分发文件，而这不是世界所需要的。
was dispense documents and that is not what the world needed.
此报价不再出现在Forrester网站上。
This quote is no longer on the Forrester website.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：archive.org有它。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Archive.org has it though.
你可以去Archive.org，它就在那里。
You can go to archive.org, it's right there.
所以很多人都听到了这个消息，
So a lot of people heard this message,
很多人都相信它，包括微软。
a lot of people believed it including Microsoft.
所以当网景自毁时，微软说很好。
So when Netscape self destructed, Microsoft said good.
我们一开始就不想要网络，所以他们解散了IE团队
We didn't want the web in the first place, so they disbanded the IE team and
让他们在X互联网上工作。
put them to work on the X Internet.
所以，他们启动了.net项目，
So, they started up the dot net project,
他们把人放在阿瓦隆上，他们在那些东西上取得了进展。
they put people on Avalon, they got moving on that stuff.
所以，令人惊讶的是网络并没有消亡，
So, the surprise was that the web didn't die,
它没有死的原因是因为JavaScript。
and the reason it didn't die was because of JavaScript.
殖民地所主张的
That what Colony was arguing for
正确的是，世界需要一个应用程序交付系统。
correctly was that the world needed an application delivery system.
他没有意识到的是网络
The thing he didn't recognize was that the web
已经是一个了，因为所有浏览器中都有JavaScript。
already was one because JavaScript was in all the browsers.
现在Java社区，以不同的方式记住了这一点。
Now Java community, remembers this differently.
Java社区对JavaScript非常生气，因为
The Java community is really angry at JavaScript for
在浏览器中并且认为这是完全不公平的
being in the browser and thinks it's completely unfair
JavaScript是浏览器中的语言。
that JavaScript was the language in the browser.
如果Java在浏览器中，事情就会有所不同，
Had Java been in the browser things would have been different,
但事实并非如此。
except that's not the way it was.
Java是浏览器中的第一种语言，Java小程序失败了。
Java was the first language in the browser and Java applets failed.
Java小程序是软件史上最大的失败。
Java applets were the biggest failure in the history of software.
总在公众面前，巨大的规模，平躺在你的脸上，
A total out there in public, huge scale, flat on your face,
我们在软件中看到的最大的失败是Java applets。
the biggest failure we've ever seen in software was Java applets.
他们应该写一次，到处跑，做所有的事情
They were supposed to write once and run everywhere and do everything and
他们没有，完全失败了。
they didn't, total failure.
另一方面，
On the other hand,
浏览器仍然存在，因为JavaScript是用来保存它的。
the browser is still in existence because JavaScript was there to save it.
所以很多使用JavaScript的人或者每个人都讨厌JavaScript。
So a lot of people who used or everybody hates JavaScript.
有些不了解JavaScript的人讨厌它，因为他们应该知道它。
There are people who don't know JavaScript who hate it because they should know it.
使用JavaScript并且讨厌它的人实际上讨厌DOM。
The people who do use JavaScript and hate it, actually hate the DOM.
DOM是浏览器呈现给JavaScript和
The DOM is the API that the browser presents to JavaScript and
这是有史以来发明的最糟糕的API之一。
it is one of the worst APIs ever invented.
这真的很糟糕，它也是由Brendan Eich设计的，他在
It's just really awful, it was designed also by Brendan Eich, he designed at
就在他设计JavaScript的同一周。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]忙碌的一周。
the same week that he designed JavaScript. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] Busy week.
道格拉斯：这是忙碌的一周，
&gt;&gt; Douglas: It was a busy week,
他被递给丹尼·古德曼的超级卡堆，这是一本书，也就是两本
he was handed Danny Goodman's HyperCard pile which is a book, that's two or
HyperCard大约有三英寸厚。
three inches thick about HyperCard.
他从未使用过HyperCard，从未使用过脚本系统，非常聪明的家伙，
He never used HyperCard, never used a scripting system, very smart guy,
学习很快。
very quick study.
他很快地读完了这本书，并认为他已经领会了它，
He read the book very quickly, and thought he got a sense of it,
如何将HyperCard模型应用于浏览器。
how do you apply the HyperCard model to the browser.
他想出了DOM，这太可怕了，太可怕了。
And he came up with the DOM and it's just awful, it's just awful.
多年来还有很多其他人对它进行了改进。
There have been many other people over the years who have improved it.
例如，最重要的贡献之一是Scott Isaacs
For example one of the most important contributions was Scott Isaacs
微软的。
of Microsoft.
他在IE 14上
He was on the IE 14 and
他看着网景公司提出的非常奇特的模型，
he looked at the very peculiar model that Netscape had came up with,
并以一种非常好的方式将其正常化。
and normalized it in a really good way.
在最初的Netscape模型中，并非所有元素都是可脚本的，并且
In the original Netscape model, not all elements were scriptable, and
那些可编写脚本的内容只能在中编写脚本
those that were scriptable were only scriptable in
一种与HyperCard书中的内容相匹配的方式。
a way that matched what was in the HyperCard book.
就像它说的，让我们让它们都以同样的方式工作
And as it said, let's make them all work the same way
这使得愚蠢的编程变得非常容易。
which made dumb programming significantly easier.
但他们从未完成的原因是因为
But they never finished the reason they never finished was because
弗雷斯特说已经结束了。
Forrester said it's done.
所以这没问题，他们都被放在其他项目上，在IE6之后，
So this is okay and they were all put on other projects and after IE6,
它只是离开了，我对这个故事很感兴趣。
it was just left and I was into the story.
所以他们知道它还没有完成，他们从来没有打算把它留在那种状态，
So they knew it wasn't finished they never intended to leave it at that state,
就是这么做的。
it's just what was done.
所以他们经常做其他事情，结果是不完整的API
So they would often did other things, as a result it's incomplete API
这是在错误的抽象级别，使用起来太可怕了。
that's at the wrong level of abstraction that's just horrible to use.